Benjamin Cato

With over a decade of experience in **front-end development**, I thrive on infusing projects with creativity and passion. I excel in collaborative environments and approach each project as a work of art, taking pride in my role as the artist.

402 Bridgepoint Ln.
Woodstock, GA 30189
(404) 374-1696
bcato3000@gmail.com
bcato3000.github.io/portfolio

EXPERIENCE

Capstone Logistics, Atlanta — *Lead front-end developer*

Jan 2024 - Present

Front-end and limited back-end web development for Vue 3 SPA for logistics and dispatching applications • Team lead for our web portal team • Liaison between UX design and developers • Mentor of junior front-end devs

Whereoware, Atlanta — Senior front-end developer

May 2023 - October 2023

Expertise in creating modular components via React and Storybook (via TypeScript) · Optimizing user interfaces for **Optimizely 12 & Sitecore 9 & 10 (CMS)** · Involved with front-end code review of PRs · Expertise in responsive web development (mobile devices and desktop) and pixel-perfect UI · Team lead for multiple front-end projects · Composition breakdown of components · AA SEO optimization · Mentor of junior front-end devs · Development for Vector and Connectwise

BrainJocks / Perficient, Alpharetta — Lead front-end developer

December 2021 - May 2023

Returned to Brainjocks / Perficient · Created SPAs via React for large-scale CMS platforms (Sitecore 8 & 9 / Optimizely 12) · Modular components and applications via React and Storybook (via TypeScript) · Responsive web development expertise (mobile devices and desktop) · AA & AAA SEO optimization · HTML5 / CSS3 / Sass / LESS and JS · Design liaison · Mentor of junior front-end devs · Client-facing and development with Cooks Children's Hospital, Publix, and Sage

Fleetcor, Atlanta — Senior front-end developer

August 2020 - December 2021

Front-end development fintech \cdot Collaborated with UI / UX designers and bridged the gap between graphical representations and technical implementation via vanilla JS, D3 Js for graphical interface \cdot Creator of global component library for enterprise purposes \cdot Provided front-end expertise for HTML / CSS / JS \cdot Unit-tests via Jest

BrainJocks / Perficient, Alpharetta — Lead front-end developer

April 2013 - July 2020

Created SPAs via React for large-scale CMS platforms (Sitecore 8 & 9 / Optimizely 11) · Modular components and applications via React and Storybook (via TypeScript) · Responsive web development expertise (mobile devices and desktop) · AA & AAA SEO optimization · HTML5 / CSS3 / Sass / LESS / JS / jQuery · Design liaison · UI instructor of SCORE (our customized front-end software) · Mentor of junior front-end devs · Client-facing and development with P&G, Honeywell,

SKILLS (years)

HTML5 (10+)

CSS3 (10+)

Sass (10+)

JavaScript (10+)

jQuery (7)

TypeScript (4)

Storybook (4)

RESTful APIs (5)

SPAs (React/Vue) (4)

Node (5)

Web components (1)

Responsive design/dev (10+)

Cross-browser (10+)

Accessibility standards (8)

Git (8)

UX (10)

Adobe creative suite (7)

Sketch App (5)

Figma (4)

Agile / Scrum (10+)

Client-facing contributor (8)

PC Windows (10+)

Mac iOS (10+)

EDUCATION

The Creative Circus, Atlanta — *Interactive Development*

Graduate: 2012 - 2013

Chattahoochee Tech, Acworth — *Computer Science*

Graduate 2001 - 2003

Kennesaw State University, Kennesaw — *Computer Science*

1997 - 2000